sunpowercorp.com 2014-12-31

# Privacy Policy | SunPower

* **General.**

This privacy policy (this " **Privacy Policy** ") is designed to inform you about the type of information that SunPower Corporation (" **we** ," " **us** ," or " **our** ") may gather or collect from you in connection with your use of this site (this "Site"). It also explains the conditions under which we use and disclose that information, and your rights in relation to that information.

The procedures for modifying or changing this Privacy Policy in the future are discussed in Section 6 of this document.

* **Children.**

This Site is not intended for children under 18 years of age. We do not knowingly collect personal information from children under 18.

* **Gathering, Use and Disclosure of Non-Personally-Identifying Information.**

We collect both Non-Personally-Identifying Information and Personally-Identifying Information from you. " **Non–Personally–Identifying Information** " is information that, without the aid of additional information, cannot be directly associated with a specific person or entity. " **Personally–Identifying Information,** " by contrast, is information such as a name or email address that, without more, can be directly associated with a specific person or entity.

  * **Gathering Non-Personally-Identifying Information.**

**(i) Web Browsers.**

Like most site operators, we gather Non-Personally-Identifying Information from you of the sort that web browsers, depending on their settings, may make available. That information includes your Internet Protocol (" **IP** ") address, operating system and browser type, and the locations of the web pages you view right before arriving at, while navigating and immediately after leaving this Site.

**(ii) Web Cookies.**

A " **Web Cookie** " is a string of information that a site stores on your computer, and your browser provides to this Site, each time you submit a query to this Site. We may use Web Cookies to track the pages that you visit during each Site session, both to help us improve your experience and to help us understand how this Site is being used.

IF YOU DO NOT WISH TO HAVE WEB COOKIES PLACED ON YOUR COMPUTER, YOU SHOULD SET YOUR BROWSER TO REFUSE WEB COOKIES BEFORE ACCESSING THIS SITE, WITH THE UNDERSTANDING THAT CERTAIN FEATURES OF THIS SITE MAY NOT FUNCTION PROPERLY WITHOUT THE AID OF WEB COOKIES. IF YOU REFUSE WEB COOKIES, YOU ASSUME ALL RESPONSIBILITY FOR ANY RESULTING LOSS OF FUNCTIONALITY.

**(iii) Web Beacons.**

A " **Web Beacon** " is an object that is embedded in a web page. It is usually invisible to you but allows site operators to check whether you have viewed a particular web page or email communication. We may place Web Beacons on pages of this Site.

You may not decline Web Beacons. However, they may be rendered ineffective by declining all cookies or modifying your browser setting to notify you each time a cookie is tendered and permit you to accept or decline cookies on an individual basis.

  * **Use of Non-Personally-Identifying Information.**

We analyze Non–Personally–Identifying Information gathered from users of this Site to help us better understand how this Site is being used. By identifying patterns and trends in usage, we are able to better design this Site to improve your experiences, both in terms of content and ease of use. We link information gathered using Non-Personally-Identifying Information to Personally-Identifying Information.

  * **Disclosure of Non-Personally-Identifying Information.**

From time to time, we may also release the Non–Personally–Identifying Information gathered from Site users in the aggregate, such as by publishing a report on trends in the usage of this Site.

* **Collection, Use and Disclosure of Personally–Identifying Information.**

As defined above, Personally-Identifying Information is information that can be directly associated with a specific person or entity. We will only collect Personally-Identifying Information that you knowingly submit to us. We will not disclose your Personally-Identifying Information to third parties unless we obtain your permission to do so at the time we collect it, except as set forth below:

  * **Registration and Other Information Provided to Us.**

When you register with this Site, you may be asked to disclose Personally–Identifying Information. You may also choose to submit Personally-Identifying Information to us when you send us an email or use any interactive features and services that we may make available from time to time on this Site.

  * **Material You Choose to Reveal in On-line Forums, Blogs, Message Boards, Chat Rooms or Similar Locations.**

You may post Personally-Identifying Information on areas of this Site that may be viewed by other users or the public, although we recommend that you do not do so. We urge you to use good judgment and not post Personally-Identifying Information that you do not want other users to know.

YOU ASSUME ALL RESPONSIBILITY FOR ANY LOSS OF PRIVACY OR OTHER HARM RESULTING FROM YOUR VOLUNTARY DISCLOSURE OF PERSONALLY-IDENTIFYING INFORMATION.

  * **Material you Choose to Reveal to Friends About Your SunPower System by Means of your mobile device**

If you purchase a SunPower system, and you register for the SunPower on-line monitoring service, you will be able to view the performance of your SunPower system on your personal page on the SunPower monitoring site. If you download the SunPower Mobile App Application to your mobile device, you will be able to view your personal SunPower system statistics on your device, and you will be able to email your friends a link to your personal SunPower system monitoring pages. If you email your friends a link to your SunPower system monitoring pages, your friends will be able to see all of your Personally-Identifying Information on these pages. The link you send to your friend will expire eight days after the date upon which you sent it to your friend. After the link expires, your friend will no longer be able to view your Personal Information on your performance pages.

  * **DMCA Infringement Notifications, Notices of Violations of Site Terms of Service and Other Communications Directed to Us.**

By submitting a Digital Millennium Copyright Act (" **DMCA** ") Infringement Notification or other communication (including communications about content stored on or transmitted through this Site), you consent to have this communication forwarded to the person or entity who stored or transmitted the content addressed by your communications in order to facilitate a prompt resolution. For notices other than DMCA Infringement Notifications, upon request, we will edit out your name and contact information. However, DMCA Infringement Notifications (including any Personally-Identifiable Information set forth in the notifications) will be forwarded as submitted to us without any deletions.

  * **Invite a Friend Feature.**

We may offer you the ability to send friends emails about this Site. If you choose to use this feature, we will only use your friends’ email addresses on a one-time basis to send the requested email and will not store or otherwise retain this information.

  * **Surveys.**

From time to time, we may also ask you to participate in surveys designed to help us improve this Site. Any Personally-Identifying Information provided to us in connection with a survey will be used only in relation to that survey, and will be disclosed to third parties not bound by this Privacy Policy only in non-personally-identifying, aggregated form.

  * **Contests, Giveaways and other Promotions.**

From time to time, we may offer you the opportunity to participate in contests, giveaways and other promotions. Any information submitted in connection with promotions will be subject to the terms of the promotion, not this Privacy Policy. You will be given the option to consent to the use of your Personally-Identifying Information at the time you sign up for the promotion. You will not be required to participate in any promotion.

  * **Security.**

We take reasonable precautions to protect the security of your information. However, neither people nor security systems are foolproof. Therefore, while we use reasonable efforts to protect your Personally-Identifying Information, we cannot guarantee its absolute security. Any unauthorized access to or use of this Site or information collected and maintained by this Site should be immediately brought to our attention by sending us an email at: [customercare@sunpower.com](mailto:customercare@sunpower.com).

  * **Storage of Personally Identifying Information Outside of the United States and Canada.**

Personally-Identifying Information may be stored on servers outside of the United States and Canada, and, as a result, may be subject to access requests from law enforcement in other jurisdictions.

  * **Other.**

Notwithstanding any other provision in this Privacy Policy, we will disclose Personally-Identifying Information in the following limited circumstances:

**(i) Employees, Third-Party Processors and Third-Party Service Providers.**

We will disclose Personally-Identifying Information to our employees, contractors, affiliates, distributors, dealers, vendors and suppliers who process Personally-Identifying Information on our behalf, participate with us in the provision or operation of this Site or provide you with services relating to your SunPower system. For example, if you sign up for our solar panel monitoring service, we combine information we collect from your PV solar system (including solar electrical production, inverter operation and home electrical consumption) with your Personal Information (such as your name, address and phone number) and provide this to dealers who provide installation, operation and maintenance services for your SunPower system.

**(ii) By Law, to Protect Rights and to Comply with Our Policies.**

We disclose Personally-Identifying Information if: (1) required to do so by law, or in response to a subpoena or court order; (2) we believe in our sole discretion that disclosure is reasonably necessary to protect against fraud, to protect the property or other rights of us or other users, third parties or the public at large; or (3) we believe that you have abused the service by using it to attack other systems or to gain unauthorized access to any other system, to engage in spamming or otherwise to violate applicable laws. For example, we may be required by law to provide your Personally-Identifying Information to the California Public Utilities Commission.

**(iii) Business Transfers; Bankruptcy.**

We reserve the right to transfer all Personally-Identifying Information in our possession to a successor entity in the event of a merger, acquisition, bankruptcy or other sale of all or a portion of our assets. Other than to the extent ordered by a bankruptcy or other court, the use and disclosure of all transferred Personally-Identifying Information will be subject to this Privacy Policy, or to a new privacy policy if you are given notice of that new privacy policy and you affirmatively opt-in to accept it. Personally-Identifying Information submitted or collected after a transfer, however, may be subject to a new privacy policy adopted by the successor entity.

**(iv) Marketing Communications.**

We may email you about products and services that we believe may be of interest to you. We may also provide your Personally-Identifying Information to third parties so that those third parties may directly contact you about products and services. If you wish to opt-out of receiving emails from us or from third parties, please follow the instructions at the bottom of each email.

* **Collection and Use of Information by Third Parties.**

Third parties are under no obligation to comply with this Privacy Policy with respect to Personally-Identifying Information that you provide directly to those third parties or that those third parties collect for themselves. We do not control the third-party sites that may be accessible through this Site. Thus, this Privacy Policy does not apply to information provided to third-party sites or gathered by the third parties that operate them. Before visiting a third-party site, whether by means of a link on this Site or otherwise, and before providing any Personally-Identifying Information to any third party, you should inform yourself of the privacy policies and practices (if any) of the third party responsible for that site, and should take those steps necessary to your discretion, to protect your privacy.

* **Tailored Messages.**

  * **Do Not Track Policy.**

California law requires that operators of website and online services disclose how they respond to a Do Not Track signal and whether other third parties may collect personally identifiable information about an individual’s online activities from their site or service.

Some browsers have incorporated “Do Not Track” features. Most of these features, when turned on, send a signal or preference to the website or online service that a user visits, indicating that the user does not wish to be tracked. Because there is not yet a common understanding of how to interpret Do Not Track signals, SunPower does not currently respond to Do Not Track signal. We continue to work with the online industry to define a common understanding of how to treat Do Not Track signals. However, in the meantime, if you do want your use of the SunPower Service not to be tracked so that we can send you targeted advertisements, please contact us as indicated in the “Contact Us” section below.

  * **Third Party Cookies.**

We allow third parties with which we have a separate agreement to use cookies and other technologies to collect information about the use of our website. These third parties include (1) business partners, who collect information when you view or interact with one of their advertisements on this Site; and (2) advertising networks, which collect information about your interests when you view or interact with one of their advertisements. The information gathered by these third parties is used to make predictions about your interests or preferences so that they can display advertisements or promotional material on this Site and on other sites across the Internet tailored to your apparent interests.

We do not do not share with these third parties any information that would readily identify about you (such as email address); however, these third parties may have access to information about your device (such as IP or MAC address). We do not have access to, or control over, the technologies that these third parties may use to collect information about your interests, and the information practices of these third parties are not covered by this Privacy Policy.

* **Privacy Policy Changes.**

Because of changes in technology and the growth and development of our business, or for other business reasons, we may need to modify this Privacy Policy from time to time. We will alert you by email if this policy is revised (if you have given us your email address), and will post a copy of the new policy with its effective date on this Site. It is therefore important that you register with the site and notify us if you change your email address. If you do not provide us with a current email address, you should regularly review this policy to ensure that you are informed of any changes.

Unless we obtain your express consent, any revised Privacy Policy will apply only to information collected after the time it takes effect, and not to information collected under any earlier Privacy Policy.

* **Access to Information.**

You have a right to contact us in order to access or update any personal information that we may store about you.

* Contact Us. 

If you wish to contact us, please contact us at the following addresses and include your name, address and email address in your correspondence to us:

**Dealers**  
SunPower Customer Service  
77 Rio Robles  
San Jose, CA 95134  
Telephone: 800-786-7693  
Email: [customercare@sunpower.com](mailto:customercare@sunpower.com)

**Residential Users**  
SunPower Customer Service  
77 Rio Robles  
San Jose, CA 95134  
Telephone: 800-786-7693  
Email: [customercare@sunpower.com](mailto:customercare@sunpower.com)

**Commercial Customers**  
SunPower Customer Service  
77 Rio Robles  
San Jose, CA 95134  
Telephone: 800-786-7693  
Email: [customercare@sunpower.com](mailto:customercare@sunpower.com)
